INTERNET CAFE
[Leorio] No good.
I've got nothing.
That two billion per Spider reward
is pretty attractive, but…
finding them will be impossible.
[Gon] Yeah…
Hey!
We could ask for concrete information
on the website.
Maybe we could even ask
about the Phantom Troupe’s
current location.
It might help,
if we offered a really big reward.
We could, but...
we don’t have nearly
enough money for that.
[Gon] Not a problem.
HUNTER LICENSE
[theme song playing]
VERY x SHARP x EYE
[narrator] Gon and his friends
are in pursuit
of the elusive Phantom Troupe
and have now obtained the funds
to buy the information they need.
[Leorio] That’s crazy!
You actually have the money!
Idiot. I can’t believe you actually pawned
your Hunter’s License.
You’re insane, you know that?
So, what do you think we should do first?
To start with we should buy ourselves
a Southernbees catalog.
Here is this year’s official
Southernbees auction catalog, gentlemen.
[Gon] Thank you!
Got it! Greed Island’s right here!
[Leorio] Seven total units on sale…
Wow. Minimum starting bid is...
8.9 billion.
No change there.
Now we just have to wait
for the information to start rollin’ in.
So first, we’ll catch one of the Spiders
and after that,
all we have to do
is make ‘em tell us
where the rest of ‘em are hiding. Easy!
What the--?
What’s wrong? Gon?
This thing is…
Look at that!
You found a Ben’s knife, huh?
Wait, what’s a Ben’s knife?
It’s a knife that a mass murderer
designed about a hundred years ago.
The guy was also a famous blacksmith.
This looks like one of his original works.
It’s a lesser known piece
a lot of rabid collectors are after.
Good eye, Gon!
I didn’t have any idea what it was.
[Killua and Leorio] Huh?
It just caught my attention is all.
I guess I got curious,
so I used Gyo on it.
And that’s when I noticed a faint aura.
What’s Gyo?
Gyo’s a form of Nen.
It’s basically when you look really,
really closely at something.
[Leorio - focusing grunt]
Wow, you weren’t kidding!
Here, let me see that.
[focusing grunt]
[Leorio] Nope. I don’t see a thing.
You will once you get
more training in Ren.
Oh, yeah! There’s another way to do it!
Do what?
Another way we can make money.
Don’t you remember
what Four Eyes said to us?
When we were at Heavens Arena?
He said some really talented people
can use Nen without even knowing!
Who the hell is Four Eyes?
[Killua] Wing.
He’s the one who taught us Nen.
So, this knife had aura.
I say we search
for other things that do, too.
Find one and it’s a good bet
that it was made by a real master!
I get it!
So, we can find hidden gems
but without having
to go through a bunch of training
to be professional appraisers!
And then we just auction off
what we find at a higher price!
If you want it,
all you gotta do is write your price down.
You mean, customers get to name
their own prices?
[hawker] Yeah.
That’s the way this market works.
You write down whatever it is
you’re willing to pay,
and when the time expires,
the item goes to whoever
had the highest bid.
See, this here is a really popular item.
Just look how the price
shot up near the end.
I get it now.
Well? Let’s get started!
Sounds good.
I’ll check out the online forums.
[Gon] Hm.
[Gon] Hmm...
This vase is pretty weird
but I’m picking up aura from it.
There’s a bid!
If there’s already a bid,
then you should enter one
that’s two and a half times higher.
You might end up bidding too high
but at least that way
you’ll scare off any rivals.
[Gon] Five hundred times two and a half…
Let me see...
Uh!
It’s the same person!
Same there?
Yeah, I found a couple of items
but both of them had bids
placed by “Zepile” already.
I bid two and a half times higher
but as soon as I did, he quadrupled it.
Then it’s not a coincidence.
No.
[Gon] What now?
We need to keep placing bids,
all the way up to the deadline.
There are two of us,
so I’m sure we’re bound to win something.
Yeah, okay.
In the end we won three and lost one.
Yeah. They got that weird vase
at the last minute.
{Killua] Not too bad,
all things considered.
Come on, let’s take ‘em
to the auction house now.
Oh, I’m terribly sorry…
but the auction house
simply can’t accept any additional items
once the catalog has been published.
You’re too late, I’m afraid.
Uh...
Can you make an exception?
See, we really had our hearts
set on auctioning off these items!
Hmm...
Perhaps you might be interested
in trying your luck over
at the dealer’s market.
[both] The Dealer’s market?
[Gon] So this is it.
The pros will be here,
so if any of these are genuine
we should get a great price.
Yeah, I know, but I really wanted
to sell these at the auction.
How much do you think we’re gonna get?
There’s only one way to find out!
Oh… You say you found these
in your storehouse?
Yeah! And my dad said
that we should sell ‘em
if the price was good enough.
These are excellent pieces.
Only fifty copies were printed,
and yours has a single-digit
serial number,
not to mention an authentic autograph.
{Killua] Yeah, we know.
[Gon] That’s where the aura
was coming from.
[shop owner]
It’s worth at least 150,000.
And look at this antique doll!
It’s in great shape.
Both the doll and box are pristine,
which raises the value.
Three hundred thousand I’d guess.
But…
I’m sorry to say this one
isn’t worth nearly as much.
[both] Oh...
[shop owner] The box and statue
are from different periods.
The box was made recently.
The statue is roughly carved
and doesn’t adhere to any theme.
I’d say it’s only worth 1,500 Jenny.
[Gon] But there’s a little aura
coming from it…
Now don’t worry.
That’s just the price as an artwork.
But the wood it’s made of
is actually quite valuable.
[Gon and Killua] Huh?
I would be more than happy
to make you an offer on it.
Sell me the painting and doll
for 420,000
and I’ll throw in another 80,000
for the wood.
So, 500,000 total?
What do you think?
There’s no rush.
Take your time.
But I doubt you’re going
to find a better offer
from anyone else around here.
In the meantime,
let me analyze this and find out
the exact age of the wood.
[man 1] Stop right there!
Put that statue down, now.
I’m sorry, but who are you?
Watch out. This guy is a scammer.
That’s a fair price
for the doll and painting
but he’s lying to your face
about the statue!
I-- I’m not lying; I swear I’m not!
You sure about that?
Because no collector
would pay 80,000 for that wood!
All you’re interested in
is the contents of that statue!
That’s actually a wooden vault.
[Gon and Killua]
Wait, are you serious?
Three hundred years ago,
secret vaults like this were a popular way
for the wealthy to evade taxes.
[Gon] I didn’t know that.
[man] If it’s the real deal,
then there should be
some sort of valuable stuffed inside.
You planned on stealing its contents
while you were just pretending
to analyze its age!
No! No, I would never do that!
[man 2] Hold on!
Do you have any proof at all
that that thing’s a genuine wooden vault?
[man 1] What was that?
It’s fairly obvious that the wood
is over 300 years old.
But all that tells us
is the age of the raw material.
It could have been carved recently.
That’s a doctoring method
called a “facelift”, boys.
A doctoring method?
He means when a counterfeiter
tries to trick a professional appraiser.
But that isn’t what I’m doing.
An amateur would never recognize
this seam here.
A seam which contains a type of glue
that was commonly used
in that time period.
You’re insisting this
is a real wooden vault, are you?
[man 1] Yeah.
But it’s possible that it’s been opened,
the contents swapped out
and then the statue was reassembled…
something we call a “transplant”.
When a counterfeiter
performs a transplant,
they put a new coat of glue
on top of the old one,
creating a secondary seal.
But only a rank amateur
would even think of trying that.
A pro would melt the glue with a flame,
then reseal it.
That would make it look like
the statue had never been opened.
It’s known as “cauterization”.
[man 1] It’s not cauterized!
If someone had used a flame,
the wood would be scorched,
or at the very least
the glue would be discolored.
Even pros would have a hard time
spotting those details.
Doesn’t prove anything.
I am a pro appraiser!
I swear by my eyes
this is a real wooden vault!
It has never been opened
and the treasure that’s inside
has never been swapped out!
Okay.
Just for the sake of argument,
let’s say it is a genuine wooden vault.
If the contents have been swapped out,
what’ll you do?
What are you willing to bet?
If you’re right, I’ll be your lackey
for the rest of my life.
[smirks]
Give it up.
[both] Oh!
[Gon and Killua] Whoa! Awesome!
[Killua] Oh… So, you’re Zepile.
Thanks a lot, Mister Zepile!
Oh, there’s no need to thank me.
It’s just a matter of give and take.
Say twenty per cent?
[both] Huh?
[Zepile] My cut of the profit
when you sell the treasure.
What?! Are you trying to rip us off,
old man?
Now that was uncalled for.
Look I’ve got to charge something
for advising you.
It’s okay.
He did help us out back there, after all.
Gimme a break, man!
We need to collect
as much Jenny as possible, remember?
We can maybe buy him lunch.
[Zepile] Oh, yeah?
Sure, works for me.
[both] Huh?
[Gon] So, Mister Zepile…
Hm?
I feel kinda bad,
so we will pay you a commission.
Dude! You’re such a pushover!
Nah. Really, it’s perfectly okay.
Just tell me one thing and we’ll be even.
What was it that made you guys
bid on all these items?
Something tipped you off.
Well? Should we tell him the truth?
Sure. It beats paying him, anyway.
[Zepile] Ah. Nen Aura, huh?
Well, if you’re being honest,
that does explain
why you purchased that statue.
It was pretty obvious you had no idea
something was hidden inside.
So why do you two need money so badly?
[Killua] We can tell you,
but not for free.
You’ve got to answer
one of our questions, too.
Great. You start.
At the auction
there’s an item we want to buy.
So, we need money.
Oh. Which item is it?
[Killua] It’s our turn now.
Three hundred million Jenny.
That’s how much
you estimated this treasure’s worth.
So, do you think
that’s how much we could get
for it at the dealer’s market?
At the dealer’s market?
I don’t really know;
they deal mainly in hard cash.
So, if you show up early on,
it’s unlikely that you’ll get
a fair price for it.
-What?!
-Seriously?
[Zepile] Now it’s my turn.
I'll repeat the question.
Which item are you looking to bid on?
It’s a video game called Greed Island.
Ah! You mean the one
that’s super expensive?
I’m real curious
about that weird vase you bought.
How much do you think that it’s worth?
What? This thing?
It’s just a piece of junk.
Totally worthless.
I don’t get why you’d want
such an expensive game.
Doesn’t it cost like six billion Jenny?
[Killua] Starts at eight point nine.
Thing is we’re trying
to find Gon’s father.
We need to buy the game
because it has a clue inside.
Oh…
[Killua] So why did you pick that vase?
Well, you knew that wooden vault
was the real thing, didn’t you?
So, you could’ve bid on that.
But you didn’t.
You bid on that weird vase instead.
Why?
Well, you see…
I sort of made this vase myself.
[both] Huh?
“Sort of” because it isn’t
my original work.
[Gon and Killua] Huh?
This is a knock-off.
In other words, it’s counterfeit.
When I was poor,
this was how I made my Jenny. Until…
I became an appraiser
and started earning money.
As soon as that happened,
I quit all of that.
But when I see
how poorly made these things are...
Oh boy, it’s really embarrassing.
I swore I’d buy them back
whenever I saw them at the market.
Any clue what a real one would cost?
[Zepile] My turn.
What does your dad do for a living?
He’s... a professional Hunter.
I asked how much a real one would cost!
-Forty, fifty K.
-[Killua grumbles]
Is that so? A pro Hunter, huh?
There are a couple of them
in the antiques community
and not one of 'em
is someone you would describe as ‘normal’.
Won’t it be impossible
for you to find him on your own?
We’ll be fine.
See, I’m a pro Hunter myself.
Wait-- really?!
‘Kay. It’s your turn
to ask us a question now.
Hmm...
Right. This one’ll be my final question.
Is there anything at all
I can help you with?
[both] Huh?
[Zepile] If you want to make money
at an auction,
you’ll need someone
with appraisal experience.
You could say that teaming up
with the right appraiser
can guarantee you a profit every time.
You choose how much you want to pay me.
Whatever you think’s fair.
How’s that?
Fine. Then you have to answer
our last question.
What made you want to help us out?
What’s in it for you?
[wry chuckle]
-It just made me happy.
-[Gon and Killua] Huh?
Felt nice that someone
was bidding on my work,
even if it is just
a worthless piece of junk.
It is not a piece of junk!
That vase you made,
it’s overflowing with your Nen,
Mister Zepile!
Aura’s common and anybody can produce it
but it’s incredibly difficult to control.
Like, really hard!
You have to concentrate
and train for a really long time.
Anybody can see how much effort
you put into making that vase.
I know I sure can!
This kind of work takes talent!
And I’m sorry
for saying it was weird earlier.
[sighs]
I can trust my eyes;
they’ve never fooled me.
When you appraise things long enough,
you can’t help but become
a good judge of character.
I look at the sellers and the buyers,
not just the goods.
If there’s one thing I’ve learned
after all this time appraising antiques,
it’s that it’s a lot harder
to appraise people.
And when I saw you,
the appraiser in me knew right away…
that I really wanted
to work with you. Truly.
So that’s my answer.
What's yours?
We’re looking forward to it.
We’ll decide on your fee
once we see what you can do.
[excited chuckle]
Great! Now that we’ve got that settled…
-First things first…
-Huh?
Can you teach me the doctoring methods
you talked about in the store earlier?
-You really want to know?
-[Gon] Yep!
Cauterizing and transplant and facelift.
Is that it or are there others?
You know something?
None of that crap matters!
[Gon] But they sound fun!
Kinda like magic tricks!
[Killua] Yeah, well,
we’re not here to have fun!
I think I get it now…
why this kid intrigued me.
He’s not concerned with
whether something is ‘good’ or ‘bad’.
When I came clean
about making counterfeits,
or when the men in the store
were talking about the vault…
I didn’t see a hint of disapproval
or greed on his face.
Not one.
But what I did see...
was pure curiosity!
If something impresses him,
he doesn’t start judging
whether it’s good or bad...
which means he’s walking a fine line.
He’s that rare kind of person
who can never truly be appraised.
Cauterization:
Definitely the hardest
doctoring method to detect.
But not too long ago
a new method surfaced.
It’s called an “autopsy”.
That’s when you plainly
reveal the opened statue
along with a fake treasure.
It’s based on most people’s assumption
that you wouldn’t open the statue
if the treasure were fake
and that makes them easy to fool.
But this method
is starting to get old now.
People were getting suspicious,
so of course
a new doctoring method emerged.
Think you can guess? Give it a try.
Oh, I know!
The statue’s fake
and the treasure inside of it
it’s fake, too!
[Zepile] Wrong!
-Oh...
-Wait. I got it!
You take the treasure out
from a different opening!
Bingo!
You start by creating a new opening
and removing the treasure.
Then, you just insert the fake treasure
and carefully seal the hole back up again.
That’s known as an “ostomy”.
An “ostomy”.
Many veteran appraisers
have been deceived by it.
If there are no signs
that the adhesive was discolored by fire,
they assume that it’s real.
And that, gentlemen,
is how you fool the pros.
Ah! What an awesome world!
[phone ringing]
Uh, hello?
A Spider?
[Leorio] Yeah. It looks real.
And there’s a video attached to it.
We’ve got two targets.
A man and a woman.
I’ll head out right now,
so meet me there.
[Gon] Got it.
-Come on. Let’s go!
-Okay.
Hey! Wait a second!
What about the auction!
You can handle it!
Yeah, just try to get us a good price!
Huh?!
All right! You can count on me!
[narrator] Gon and Killua
have had their eyes opened
to a brand-new world.
And they are about to make contact
with the Phantom Troupe.
[theme song playing]
[Gon] Coming up:
-Gon...
-[Killua] ...and Killua’s…
[both] Hunterpedia!
-I’m Gon!
-I’m Killua!
[both] And this is our Hunterpedia!
Today we’ll introduce Shizuku.
Phantom Troupe member
with a vacuum cleaner named Blinky.
But it can suck up the living!
And its capacity is huge!
Where do you go
if you get sucked up in it?
Nobody knows!
[Gon] Next time:
“Pursuit x and x Analysis.”
-Right or left?
-[Killua] Right.
-[Gon] Do we follow the man or the woman?
-[Killua] The woman.
-[Gon] What’s better, red or blue?
-[Killua] You pick!